where do you see the role of grassroots
movements the permaculture movement or
the eco village movement in this shift
towards sustainability mm-hmm well it's
clear that this current high consumption
high style that we are engaged in is is
not going to last much longer it's
reached reaching the limits of the
Earth's capacity to bear it so we're
going to have to do something we're
going to have to live in much simpler
ways and this is where permaculture and
the eco village movement comes in and
we've got to to live in the right way
with an animate earth with it means a
life that's simpler and much much more
connected with the cycles of nature with
growing food with earthen buildings with
organic buildings with homemade clothes
with all of those things and this is
where permaculture can help us to a to
survive because we're not going to be
able to survive and any other way once
this civilization collapses which seems
pretty likely and be more than to
survive and to actually develop a deep
relationship with the earth because
those are organic structures that are
made those will gain houses that are
made say in permaculture near the coal
houses Strawberry houses for
permaculture Gardens all of those ways
of living and dealing with the earth in
themselves and body the animate earth
within them once you once you're living
inside a structure like that once you're
growing your food in that sort of
permaculture ish way those those
purchases actually teach you about the
animal nature of the earth in a physical
experiential way which you can't get
simply through reading books so in other
words in order to really experience what
what this world is you have to live in a
way that's consistent with it and
harmonious with it and this is where
they could village movement comes in
the permaculture movement comes in so
two levels one is a superficial level
well we it's the only way we're going to
survive in the future in our
civilization collapses and to the deeper
level it's the only way that we're
actually going to experientially
understand how we can live with the
earth or what this earth really is we
can't experience it once with summer
sitting in a jet plane or a Mercedes
Benz but we can experience it when we're
living in Iran hot made out of straw
bale all-natural materials is your
vision of the future one where we're
really going back to just natural
materials and a set of future primitive
lifestyle or do you do you see a way
that we might be able to bring what was
good about these traditional cultures
back into a modern technological culture
and and somehow marry the two I think we
can neither - it depends how many people
you need to have Oh
but speaking ideally yes I think we can
marry the two but I think it would be a
much more organic relationship with
nature we may have a high tech we
probably have computers but we'll be
using those computers in buildings that
have made largely out of natural
materials that buildings that when we
sit in them are constantly reminding us
of the Earth from which the materials
were taken that doesn't mean to say that
we can't have a sophisticated buildings
I mean I think many of the buildings
even of the Victorian age embodied that
sort of organic feeling I don't think
we'll be sitting in glass-fronted
skyscrapers in that in that time I mean
there might still be some left that we
have to use ideally I think they'll have
moved away from that kind of a intense
hi-tech at least an hour an hour
buildings